□ (+44) 07429 241034 | Signal jose.alberto.coelho@gmail.com | 😭 www.jacoelho.com | 🖸 jacoelho

Summary_

Platform Engineer with a 10+ year tech career that includes extensive experience designing and implementing highly available and maintainable infrastructure solutions and effective processes for continuous integration, delivery, and deployment. Dynamic skill set includes web development, security, and networking on Unix and Windows systems.

Work Experience

Senior Platform Engineer - Sky Betting & Gaming

Leeus

SKY BETTING & GAMING IS A BRITISH-BASED GAMBLING COMPANY.

Mar. 2016 - Present

- Lead developer for an online casino system that mediates interactions (e.g. user account balance checks, updating customer wallets) between games providers and internal systems allowing hundreds of game plays per second. Built using Go, Kafka/Kafka-Connect, and MySQL.
- · Developed multiple metrics exporters and improved monitoring infrastructure to help increase systems visibility.
- Built an internal application using Go and Vue.js to redirect traffic and disable gameplay during planned outages by setting or removing attributes from load balancers.
- Wrote common reusable infrastructure configurations to reduce AWS new services deployment time.
- · Served as internal SME for Chef and rewrote several cookbooks to modernize coding practices and standards.
- Developed a scalable Selenium grid that enables hundreds of tests to run every day.
- Analyzed delivery pipelines to identify and resolve pain points. Wrote Groovy (Jenkins) code to orchestrate and parallelize, reducing deployment time and increasing stability.
- Revamped logging processes to improve ability to investigate and resolve issues.
- Advised various development teams to promote the adoption of operations best practices.
- Promoted from Platform Engineer to Senior Platform Engineer in July 2018.

Automation Engineer - Linkedcare

Lishon

LINKEDCARE WAS A PORTUGUESE STARTUP IN THE E-HEALTH SUBSECTOR.

Nov. 2014 - Mar. 2016

- Wrote and supported infrastructure code for public cloud providers AWS and DigitalOcean.
- · Implemented and maintained Ansible configuration management spanning several AWS cloud environments.
- Designed and built a local development environment supported by Docker and CoreOS.
- Implemented Continuous Integration with Shippable and CircleCI and worked with development teams to improve workflows and release processes for new features.

Systems/Application Administrator - Portugal Telecom

Lisbor

PORTUGAL TELECOM IS THE LARGEST TELECOMMUNICATIONS SERVICE PROVIDER IN PORTUGAL.

June 2013 - Nov. 2014

- Deployed and managed provisioning infrastructure for SaaS/laaS services and wrote Powershell automation scripts.
- Provided third-level support for customers and partners in Portugal and Brazil.
- Developed a software licensing tool to ensure compliance.

Systems/Network Administrator - Refer Telecom

Lichon

REFER TELECOM IS A RAIL TELECOMMUNICATIONS AND SERVICE PROVIDER.

Oct. 2011 - June 2013

- Designed, implemented, and managed redundant multi-site data center networking and Linux (DNS, email) servers.
- Installed and supported CheckPoint and Cisco ASA/FWSM firewalls.
- Developed Cisco automations using Jinja2/Python and implemented version control for all switches and routers.

Prior work includes four combined years as IT Security Administrator and Network/Linux Administrator.

Skills_

AWS, Linux (Centos, Debian, Ubuntu, CoreOS), Kubernetes, Rancher, Windows Server, Cisco, Checkpoint, NGINX, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Apache, IIS, Bind, Active Directory, Redis, HAProxy, Monit, Chef, Jenkins, CloudFormation, Terraform, Packer, Vagrant, Docker, Ansible, Travis, CircleCI, Shippable, Serverspec, Bats, Git, Ruby, Go, Python, Clojure, Bash, Powershell, Expect

Education

Coursework in Computer Engineering at Instituto Superior Técnico